PROFILE

Ad operations professional with experience in publisher-side ad implementation and QA across desktop, mobile, tablet, and streaming channels. I am motivated to bridge usability needs with broader business objectives and client goals with a technical grasp for product and sales workflows.

EDUCATION

New York University

B.S. - Media, Culture & Communication

September 2012 - December 2015

University Honors Scholar / Founder's Day Award Recipient, Steinhardt Global Scholars Program

Columbia Engineering

Certificate - UX/UI

August 2020 - expected February 2021

24-week long part-time immersive bootcamp course training on UX/UI design methodology, user-centric design research, visual prototyping and wireframing, interface design, storyboarding, visual design theory, web prototyping with HTML5 and CSS, interaction design, and agile project management and product development

SKILLS & CERTIFICATION

Google Ads Display Certification

Issued October 2020

TOOLS

Adobe XD Adobe Photoshop InVision Figma Google Suite Microsoft Suite

WORK EXPERIENCE

Disney Streaming Services

Ad Operations Trafficker, NHL

August 2018 - Present

- Act as liaison with ad sales, client services and NHL business partners
 regarding tracking, scheduling, troubleshooting, delivery, and billing of
 campaigns across digital properties for NHL.com, NHL.tv, and 31 individual
 hockey team web and app platforms
- Execute all media trafficking needs by scheduling and maintaining placement
 and rotation of creative throughout the lifetime of direct, partner-sold, and
 programmatic campaigns in ad server (Google Ad Manager) and
 programmatic platforms; managing post-launch performance with client
 services team via reporting analysis and delivery optimizations
- Thoroughly test and QA mid-roll assets within proprietary server-side ad insertion streaming platform (AdEngine) for NHL.tv against creative spec requirements, ensuring quality transcodes and seamless ad stitching in live game environments for direct sold campaigns (VAST validation, bitrate/frame rate/format analysis)
- Coordinate with client services in post-sale linear campaign executions (brand allocations, flighting) for NHL Network in broadcast order management system (Broadway)
- Support ad server-related product roll-outs and testing as needed (QA redesigned hockey team experiences for desktop/mobile web, native ads)
- Work closely with internal teams on establishing processes from scratch on implementation and best practices for trafficking, testing, and reporting
- Assist Disney+ content and business operations teams with ad-hoc reporting and project requests in order to offer additional support surrounding global launch timelines as needed

The Weather Company, an IBM Business

Campaign Specialist

October 2017 - August 2018

- Schedule and assign creative assets into DFPP across TWC's proprietary desktop & mobile platforms (standard display, video, native, custom product and sponsorship ads) for direct national sales, hyperlocal, and house campaigns
- Maintain responsibility for accurate & timely launch of accounts across multiple verticals for a ~\$4M total revenue portfolio
- Analyze reporting and utilize technical tools (such as Charles, Ghostery, Advalidation), to ensure that all technical aspects of ad execution are running seamlessly and within spec, thus meeting client expectations and securing successful overall campaign performance (impression pixels & discrepancies, viewability tracking, measurement studies, video error rate, rich media file components, etc)
- Investigate any post-launch delivery issues with Program Management, Ad Product, & Ad Tech teams
- Communicate technical specifications and publisher creative standards internally to account teams and campaign managers

Ad Ops Associate

January 2016 - September 2017

- Supported campaign managers and specialists in all executional functions related to post-sales ad ops processes
- Owned multiple ad hoc interdisciplinary projects -- such as house, local partner, and creative troubleshooting requests -- thus developing in-depth and holistic knowledge regarding large-scale operations strategy